<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Jayasudha Jayakumaran</title><link>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Jayasudha Jayakumaran</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Asia Works: Success and Failure in the World's Most Dynamic Region</title><link>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/how-asia-works/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/how-asia-works/</guid><description>Not having a background in Economics definitely made this a tough read for me. I read through this book with the intent of having at least a few takeaways and not to completely internalize every single idea put forward by the author who had spent decades on the topic. Hope this review helps outsiders like me who are interested to see how policy making molds the society. Joe Studwell&amp;rsquo;s book has 4 chapters - first 3 focusing on three critical factors of development in Asia and 4th focusing solely on how these 3 factors played out in China.</description></item><item><title>Never Split the Difference</title><link>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/never-split-the-difference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/never-split-the-difference/</guid><description>This is a book on negotiation written by Chris Voss, an expert in negotiation skills who has been teaching the same in B-Schools and Corporations. The book is an interesting collection of anecdotes where the author’s negotiation skills have helped him tackle crucial conversations during his career at FBI as a negotiator. Each chapter goes into depth on each technique that the author has developed over the years. It is an interesting read for anyone looking for a mental model to approach difficult conversations.</description></item><item><title>Homo Deus: A brief History of Tomorrow</title><link>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/homo-deus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/homo-deus/</guid><description>Homo Deus : A brief History of Tomorrow is a much though-provoking book written by Yuval Noah Harari in 2015. First published in Hebrew and later in English. In my previous post, I tried to highlight a few important takeaways from Harari’s first book – Sapiens: A brief history of humankind. Homo Deus is not a sequel to Sapiens in a strict sense but there are many topics which are a continuum of what the author has touched upon in Sapiens.</description></item><item><title>Sapiens</title><link>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/sapiens/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/sapiens/</guid><description>Sapiens by Yuval Noah Harari is so popular and in almost everyone’s to-read list that I waited for months for it to come back in-stock on amazon but finally, the hold placed on a copy at my nearest library a few months ago paid off. I landed this minimalist hardcover book which just has a human thumbprint on front cover three weeks back. The book is about how homo sapiens (which also means wise men) got to where we are today and how we are leaving our fingerprints on the planet just like the one on the book’s cover.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/the-impossible-country/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjayakumaran.github.io/posts/the-impossible-country/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>